<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authors on Datafortress.cloud</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/de/author/</link><description>Recent content in Authors on Datafortress.cloud</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>de-de</language><managingEditor/><webMaster/><atom:link href="https://datafortress.cloud/de/author/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Justin Guese</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/de/author/justin-guese/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author/><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/de/author/justin-guese/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I, Justin Güse, am the founder of &lt;strong>Datafortress.cloud&lt;/strong>. After working for Porsche Holding in an &lt;strong>innovation/data science division&lt;/strong>, where I developed many projects ranging from Big Data to Virtual Reality (see &lt;a href="https://datafortress.cloud/project">portfolio&lt;/a>), I decided to found my own company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During my time at Porsche, I observed that many agencies or consultants &lt;strong>do not have the main goal to satisfy their clients’ needs&lt;/strong> as the main priority, but rather how to achieve the minimal needed tasks in the shortest amount of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consultants were analyzing the situation but left us alone when it came to the application or the development. Oftentimes agencies struggled because the person executing a project is different from a consultant, which caused a lot of confusion and errors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is my belief, that great projects can only be achieved if an &lt;strong>agency both plans/consults a partner, and offers the execution, or at least recommended partners as well&lt;/strong>. We will not just propose an insane plan and leave the execution to someone else – we plan thoroughly what is possible and how it can become a reality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Furthermore, it is my belief, that if I will &lt;strong>take the extra mile&lt;/strong> to fully satisfy a contract, that we can establish a &lt;strong>trust-based relationship&lt;/strong> and maybe even start new projects together with the budget that might be saved due to our cooperation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>