<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Datafortress.cloud</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Datafortress.cloud</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 07:10:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datafortress.cloud/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unlocking the Potential of Machine Learning with Private Cloud Services: Real-World Case Studies</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/case-study-real-world-applications-private-cloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 07:10:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/case-study-real-world-applications-private-cloud/</guid><description>Unlocking the Potential of Machine Learning with Private Cloud Services: Real-World Case Studies Welcome to the world of data-driven business success!</description></item><item><title>Maximizing Cost Savings in the Cloud: How to Run Kubernetes without a Load Balancer</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/kubernetes-without-load-balancer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 07:10:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/kubernetes-without-load-balancer/</guid><description>Maximizing Cost Savings in the Cloud: How to Run Kubernetes without a Load Balancer When it comes to running Kubernetes in the cloud, one of the most significant costs can come from using a load balancer for each service.</description></item><item><title>Unleashing the Power of Private Clouds: Comparing the Top Providers and Their Offerings</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/private-cloud-providers-comparison/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 07:10:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/private-cloud-providers-comparison/</guid><description>Unleashing the Power of Private Clouds: Comparing the Top Providers and Their Offerings In the world of technology, the private cloud has become a game-changer for businesses looking to streamline their operations, increase efficiency, and protect sensitive data.</description></item><item><title>Going from Wordpress to serverless, unhackable high-speed static websites</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/wordpress-to-serverless-highspeed-scalable-unhackable/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 11:10:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/wordpress-to-serverless-highspeed-scalable-unhackable/</guid><description>Going from Wordpress to serverless, unhackable high-speed static websites I have been building websites in the past, but have always been struggling with the slow performance of WordPress.</description></item><item><title>Face Detection using MTCNN</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/face-detection-using-mtcnn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 07:10:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/face-detection-using-mtcnn/</guid><description>What is MTCNN MTCNN is a python (pip) library written by Github user ipacz, which implements the [paper Zhang, Kaipeng et al.</description></item><item><title>How to deploy an automated trading bot using the Facebook Prophet Machine Learning model to AWS Lambda (serverless)</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/how-to-deploy-an-automated-trading-bot-using-the-facebook-prophet-machine-learning-model-to-aws-lambda-serverless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/how-to-deploy-an-automated-trading-bot-using-the-facebook-prophet-machine-learning-model-to-aws-lambda-serverless/</guid><description>I divided this post into the “Why did I do it” and the “Technical How To”.</description></item><item><title>How to integrate 3D models into websites and Quick View for Android and iOS devices</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/3d-model-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 11:10:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/3d-model-integration/</guid><description>Integrating a 3D model into a website using Quick View for Android and iOS Try it out: Rotate the 3D object below, or look at it in AR using your phone or even VR if a VR-glass is connected to your computer.</description></item><item><title>Docker Compose vs. Kubernetes vs. Traditional Hosting: What's the Best Way to Host Your Application?</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/kubernetes-vs-docker-vs-vms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 07:11:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/kubernetes-vs-docker-vs-vms/</guid><description>Battle of the Containerization Tools: Kubernetes vs Docker Compose vs VM Hosting Docker: The Lightweight, Portable Option for Hosting Applications Docker: Leightweight, proof-of-concept, running multiple programs on one server</description></item><item><title>Enhancing stock data for your Python Algorithmic Trading Model</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/enhancing-stock-data-for-your-python-algorithmic-trading-model/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/enhancing-stock-data-for-your-python-algorithmic-trading-model/</guid><description>Your first steps building a trading algorithm Let us say you are planning to build your own algorithmic trading model.</description></item><item><title>How to set up Anaconda and Jupyter Notebook the right way</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/how-to-set-up-anaconda-and-jupyter-notebook-the-right-way/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/how-to-set-up-anaconda-and-jupyter-notebook-the-right-way/</guid><description>If Anaconda (conda) and Jupyter Notebook (Jupyter Lab) are set up the right way the combination of them can become the perfect team, where you are able to easily switch between Deep Learning conda environments.</description></item><item><title>The 5 typical applications of Augmented Reality</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/the-5-typical-applications-of-augmented-reality/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/the-5-typical-applications-of-augmented-reality/</guid><description>What is AR? Why do I need Augmented Reality as a company?</description></item><item><title>How To - Installing Arch Linux the easy way with encrypted drives</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/howto-install-arch-linux-the-easy-way/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 07:10:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/howto-install-arch-linux-the-easy-way/</guid><description>Installing Arch Linux the easy way with encrypted drives for Deep Learning The benefits of Arch Linux In my other post, “How To: Ditching Ubuntu in favor of Arch Linux for a Deep Learning Workstation”, I have been explaining why I switched from Ubuntu to Arch Linux for my Machine Learning workstation.</description></item><item><title>Top 6 best Cloud Storage services – Free, Paid and for Businesses</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/top-6-cloud-storage-solutions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/top-6-cloud-storage-solutions/</guid><description>Why should I store my data in the cloud?
The computing industry has moved gradually away from local storage to remote, server-based storage and computing since the rise of the internet — what has been known as the cloud.</description></item><item><title>How To - Ditching Ubuntu in favor of Arch Linux for a Deep Learning Workstation</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/howto-arch-linux-deeplearning-workstation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/howto-arch-linux-deeplearning-workstation/</guid><description>How To: Ditching Ubuntu in favor of Arch Linux for a Deep Learning Workstation Why should I ditch Ubuntu?</description></item></channel></rss>