<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud on Datafortress.cloud</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/tags/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in cloud on Datafortress.cloud</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor/><webMaster/><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 11:10:07 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datafortress.cloud/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Going from Wordpress to serverless, unhackable high-speed static websites</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/wordpress-to-serverless-highspeed-scalable-unhackable/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 11:10:07 +0600</pubDate><author>Justin Guese</author><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/wordpress-to-serverless-highspeed-scalable-unhackable/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="going-from-wordpress-to-serverless-unhackable-high-speed-static-websites">Going from Wordpress to serverless, unhackable high-speed static websites&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I have been building websites in the past, but have always been struggling with the slow performance of WordPress. If it is loaded with plugins, it will need quite some resources and can be a pain if you are just developing an idea on a small server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, safety is of concern as well, and as a system that &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordPress">33,6% of websites are using&lt;/a>, it is quite attractive for hackers to find exploits and other issues in it.
But again, as it is massively popular, there is almost every time a plugin for the issues you are having, which makes it easy to use, and a great &amp;ldquo;all-in-one&amp;rdquo; tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="idea-1-improving-wordpress-development">Idea 1: Improving WordPress Development&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the first things I did in the past has been to develop WordPress locally (e.g. &lt;a href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2018/04/wordpress-local-development-beginners-setup-deployment/">see this AWS post&lt;/a>), and then just publish the result on a server. Programming and writing speeds increased enormously, but the uploading part proved to be a problem, as WordPress links are usually &amp;ldquo;hardwired&amp;rdquo; into the SQL database it uses. Meaning all my links were referring to &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.datafotress.cloud">https://www.datafotress.cloud&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; (My Computer) instead of the target domain. There are ways to solve this, like rewriting your URLs in SQL, or using rewriting htaccess rules to refer &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; URLs to the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; ones, but still, it was a lot of struggle to get going.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="idea-2-online-development-with-offloaded-media-files">Idea 2: Online Development with Offloaded Media files&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This URL rewriting issue got on my nerves real quick, and local development is bad for multiple developers. That is why I decided to &amp;ldquo;go online&amp;rdquo; again, and work &amp;ldquo;with the cloud&amp;rdquo;. The architecture I followed has been to deploy one development server, that is only accessible to developers, and to upload media files to shared storage (AWS S3) from which end users are pulling the media files. As media files (pictures, videos, &amp;hellip;) are the most demanding parts of WordPress, speed increased drastically, and additionally, it has been easy to set up a CDN on top of it, which basically means the media files are deployed all over the world at unlimited capacity (basically serverless). This means, that one user in e.g. Puerto Rico does not need to access my server in Frankfurt, but has a &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo; copy close to him. Additionally, as the &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo; part of WordPress has been &amp;ldquo;outsourced&amp;rdquo;, only &amp;ldquo;small&amp;rdquo; servers were needed to handle PHP requests and the &amp;ldquo;back-office&amp;rdquo; parts of WordPress. Feel free to ask me more about it in the comments or a direct message, or &lt;a href="https://devops.com/hosting-scalable-wordpress-on-aws/">check out a similar approach by AWS&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://datafortress.cloud/images/blog/Webp.net-resizeimage.png" alt="Architecture for wordpress on AWS">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together with Autoscaling, this seemed to be the most ideal setup for WordPress, and it proved great. BUT&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You still had to check for Plugin Updates, Security, and Monitoring in general. Even though AWS helps a lot to make this architecture quite resilient and fast, there is still a high operational demand. Additionally, running a separate development, database, load balancing, and so on the server can be quite cost expensive, especially for a website that does not have many users.
And what did Werner Vogels say at re:invent 2015?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;No server is easier to manage than no server&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Werner Vogels at re:invent 2015&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="excursion-a-brief-history-of-the-code-of-web">Excursion: A brief history of the Code of web&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>WordPress is great for writers and editors, but form the perspective of a solution architect it is not great. Why? Even though everything is clickable, easy to handle, and so on, all resources and information are pulled from a database in the background, even though if it is pulled for the 100000th time this day. There are methods to reduce the query load on SQL databases, like Redis and Memcached, but why should I &amp;ldquo;calculate&amp;rdquo; the same webpage for every single user? &amp;ldquo;Back in the day&amp;rdquo;, websites did just load in seconds (except someone has been on the phone) and they were super small - what has changed? Together with new design demands, today&amp;rsquo;s websites are full of effects and designs that are heavy on computational resources. Even though this is definitely an improvement to the 90s black and white style, loading times of websites increased dramatically - especially as the world&amp;rsquo;s connection standard is still mobile network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To render all the effects, PHP code is used in the background, which is code executed on the server itself. Meaning every time a user connects to a website, the server is calculating the website it is going to show to the user. The 90s version of websites featured just plain HTML code, which are basically simple instructions to the browser on how to handle things. Like the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> tag tells the browser this is a heading, and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> is a paragraph. No (sorry for reducing complexity!) calculations are needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, Javascript and CSS go a similar path as CSS describes design in a similar approach to HTML, and Javascript is executed not on the server, but on the client-side. Meaning the server does not calculate itself, but &amp;ldquo;sends instructions&amp;rdquo; to the client&amp;rsquo;s browser (e.g. your phone).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why don&amp;rsquo;t we use just HTML, Javascript, and CSS? PHP enables us to do a lot of things and allows for content creation frameworks like WordPress to make our lives easier. But the efficient way to produce websites would be to generate them once and then just distribute them already rendered to the masses.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="idea-4-going-back-to-the-roots">Idea 4: Going back to the roots&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So am I saying we should go back to the black and white HTML pages of the 90s? Of course not, but the combination of HTML and CSS can produce great results, and Javascript becomes more and more capable to handle processes only PHP could handle in the past. And if calculations are needed, there are great new serverless possibilities available like AWS Lambda (check out my blog for some applications of Lambda).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Going back to the main topic, I have decided to write my blog and any future websites in plain HTML, CSS, and JS, as I do not need to&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>manage a server&lt;/strong> - I can just host it for almost free on Github or AWS S3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>worry about high-demands&lt;/strong> - S3 and Github scale automatically, meaning if thousands of visitors arrive on my website it will not crash my server
pay much - as I do not need as many calculations as with WordPress, running this blog is completely free&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>do not need to worry about security issues&lt;/strong> - my blog is basically unhackable&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Additionally, the website is blazingly fast, with a Google Pagespeed score of 100%, which has a great effect on page ranking as well, as Google favors high-speed websites. The only reason why the current score is down to 90%, is that I decided to include CRM and tracking tools on my blog. When was the last time you saw a free website achieving this score?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, it is just great, but am I writing all the HTML code by myself?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introducing-static-website-generators">Introducing: Static Website Generators&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Of course not, and luckily there are great tools to handle this for me. Static website builders like &lt;a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a> help a lot to let you basically just type in Markdown language (basically a simple txt file) and convert your texts into HTML and a nice website. The code is just calculated once and can be uploaded to a server, or Github pages and AWS S3 right away to be completely serverless. &lt;a href="https://datafortress.cloud/project/serverless-static-website/">How does it work? Check out my case studies on my blog for an in-depth explanation&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It feels great to not worry about uptime, scaling, and security anymore. Is it harder than WordPress? It depends. As this technology just develops, there is a rethinking to be done if you worked with WordPress and others in the past, but again there are many great tools that make static website builders similar to the &amp;ldquo;known&amp;rdquo; WordPress environment, like forestry.io for example. How? &lt;a href="https://datafortress.cloud/project/serverless-static-website/">Check out my blog at www.datafortress.cloud to see the in-depth explanation&lt;/a>.
For now, I would be interested if you ever tried to go serverless, or what your experiences with WordPress are. &lt;a href="https://datafortress.cloud/contact/">Shoot me a message, or write a comment below&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docker Compose vs. Kubernetes vs. Traditional Hosting: What's the Best Way to Host Your Application?</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/kubernetes-vs-docker-vs-vms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 07:11:46 +0200</pubDate><author>Justin Guese</author><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/kubernetes-vs-docker-vs-vms/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="battle-of-the-containerization-tools-kubernetes-vs-docker-compose-vs-vm-hosting">Battle of the Containerization Tools: Kubernetes vs Docker Compose vs VM Hosting&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="docker-the-lightweight-portable-option-for-hosting-applications">Docker: The Lightweight, Portable Option for Hosting Applications&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Docker: Leightweight, proof-of-concept, running multiple programs on one server&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Docker has become a popular tool for application development and deployment in recent years. Its popularity can be attributed to its lightweight, portable nature, making it an excellent choice for hosting applications. Unlike traditional virtual machines, Docker containers do not require a complete operating system to be installed, resulting in a much smaller footprint. This feature also enables the use of the same container across different environments, making it easy to move from development to production. Additionally, Docker containers are easily scalable, allowing you to add or remove resources as needed. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a cost-effective and efficient way to host your applications, Docker might be the perfect solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a containerization technology that enables developers to create, package, and distribute applications in an isolated and portable environment. In simpler terms, it&amp;rsquo;s a way of bundling an application with all its dependencies into a single package, making it easy to move between different environments or host on multiple servers. For CEOs, this means that Docker can simplify the deployment of new applications, reduce infrastructure costs, and increase the reliability and security of their software. By using Docker, you can easily create and manage containers, ensuring that your applications run consistently and reliably across any infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Compared to traditional hosting in Virtual Machines (VMs), Docker offers several advantages. One of the most significant is its lightweight and portable nature. Docker containers are much smaller in size than VMs and require fewer resources to run. This makes them faster to deploy, more efficient to manage, and easier to scale up or down as needed. Docker also provides an isolated and standardized environment for applications, ensuring that they run the same way across different servers. However, there are also potential downsides to using Docker, such as the need for additional expertise to manage containers and potential security concerns if not configured properly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But isn&amp;rsquo;t Kubernetes the same as Docker? How do they differ?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="kubernetes-the-scalable-solution-for-large-scale-container-management">Kubernetes: The Scalable Solution for Large-Scale Container Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Kubernetes: Docker, but running on multiple machines. Self-repair, Security, Automation, Enterprise&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Kubernetes is a popular open-source platform for automating container deployment, scaling, and management. It is designed to manage large-scale containerized applications, providing a highly scalable, portable, and extensible platform. Kubernetes has become the industry standard for container orchestration, allowing organizations to manage their containers across multiple hosts, automate deployment, and ensure availability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The platform works by abstracting the underlying infrastructure and providing a container-centric approach to application management. This makes it easier for developers to deploy and manage their applications without worrying about the underlying infrastructure. Kubernetes provides a highly resilient and self-healing system, allowing for automatic failover and reducing the risk of downtime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kubernetes has a number of advantages over traditional hosting solutions. Firstly, it is highly scalable, allowing organizations to deploy and manage a large number of containers across multiple hosts. This enables organizations to quickly and easily scale their applications as needed. Additionally, Kubernetes is highly portable, enabling organizations to move their applications between cloud providers and on-premises data centers without having to make significant changes to the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, Kubernetes can be more complex to set up and manage compared to traditional hosting solutions. It requires a more significant investment of time and resources to set up and manage the platform, and it may not be suitable for smaller applications or organizations with limited resources. Additionally, Kubernetes has a steeper learning curve for developers, who need to become proficient in the platform&amp;rsquo;s architecture and APIs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, Kubernetes is an excellent solution for organizations that need to manage large-scale containerized applications. It provides a highly scalable, portable, and extensible platform that can be used to manage containers across multiple hosts. However, organizations should carefully consider their needs and resources before deciding to adopt the platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="vms-the-traditional-hosting-solution-still-holding-strong">VMs: The Traditional Hosting Solution Still Holding Strong&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>VMs: Low knowledge required, high resource usage, instable&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Virtual machines, or VMs, have been the backbone of hosting applications for years, and continue to be a reliable and trusted option for businesses. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the pros and cons of using VMs as a hosting solution, and compare them to newer options like Docker and Kubernetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the main advantages of using VMs is their stability and security. Each VM operates in its own isolated environment, so any issues or breaches on one VM won&amp;rsquo;t affect the others. VMs are also highly customizable, allowing businesses to create and configure VMs to meet their specific needs. However, VMs can be resource-intensive, requiring a dedicated server to run, and can be slow to scale up or down in response to changing demands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Compared to newer options like Docker and Kubernetes, VMs may seem outdated, but they still have their place. VMs are ideal for running legacy applications that may not be compatible with newer container-based solutions, and they are often more affordable than other hosting options. However, the lack of scalability and agility of VMs may be a disadvantage for businesses that require rapid deployment and frequent updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, VMs remain a solid choice for businesses that need a reliable, secure hosting solution for legacy applications or other specific use cases. However, for those looking for a more agile and scalable solution, newer options like Docker and Kubernetes may be a better fit. It&amp;rsquo;s important to evaluate your business&amp;rsquo;s specific needs and requirements before choosing a hosting solution, and to weigh the pros and cons of each option carefully.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pros-and-cons-of-docker-kubernetes-and-vms-for-application-hosting">Pros and Cons of Docker, Kubernetes, and VMs for Application Hosting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Summarizing our above findings, we can say that Docker is a lightweight, portable solution that allows for application deployment in a consistent manner across different environments. One of the key advantages of Docker is its ability to isolate and containerize applications, which allows for increased security and flexibility. Additionally, because Docker containers are so lightweight, they can be deployed quickly, making it a great solution for small to medium-scale applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, Kubernetes is designed for large-scale container management and is a scalable solution that can be used to orchestrate containerized applications across a large number of nodes. Kubernetes is a great solution for organizations that need to manage a large number of containers across multiple environments. Its key features include load balancing, automatic scaling, and self-healing capabilities, making it a great solution for mission-critical applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, traditional VMs offer a reliable and stable solution for hosting applications. VMs have been around for a long time and are well-understood by IT professionals, making them a safe choice for mission-critical applications. While VMs may not be as flexible as Docker or Kubernetes, they can still offer good performance and scalability, making them a great option for organizations that have already invested in the technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, the choice between Docker, Kubernetes, and traditional VMs will depend on your specific needs and requirements. While Docker is a great choice for smaller applications, Kubernetes is designed for larger, more complex environments, and traditional VMs are a reliable and stable option for mission-critical applications. It&amp;rsquo;s important to weigh the pros and cons of each solution carefully and consult with experts if necessary to ensure you make the right choice for your organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-verdict-which-containerization-solution-is-right-for-your-business">The Verdict: Which Containerization Solution Is Right for Your Business?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re still unsure which option is best for your business, don&amp;rsquo;t worry - our experts at DataFortress.cloud are here to help. We understand that each business has unique needs and requirements, and we offer personalized consultation to help you make the best decision for your specific situation. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re interested in Docker, Kubernetes, or VMs, we can help you identify the pros and cons of each option and determine which one is the right fit for your business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To get started, simply visit our &lt;a href="https://datafortress.cloud/contact">contact page and reach out to us. We&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to answer any questions you may have and provide you with the guidance you need to make an informed decision. At DataFortress.cloud, we&amp;rsquo;re committed to helping you achieve your goals and thrive in the ever-changing world of application hosting.&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top 6 best Cloud Storage services – Free, Paid and for Businesses</title><link>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/top-6-cloud-storage-solutions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Justin Guese</author><guid>https://datafortress.cloud/blog/top-6-cloud-storage-solutions/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Why should I store my data in the cloud?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The computing industry has moved gradually away from local storage to remote, server-based storage and computing since the rise of the internet — what has been known as the cloud. Look at music and films: from media, we used to play them, and now they are downloaded from networks. Through storing your own data and media files in the cloud, you will enjoy the same benefits of viewing and uploading from anywhere. The advantages are increases in efficiency and decreased demands for local storage. We have rounded up the best providers for cloud storage and file-sharing or file synchronization to help you determine which one is right for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you do not have a platform in the cloud to store and synchronize your data yet, you should consider it seriously. What you choose depends on the types of files that you save, how much protection you need, how you intend to share with others, and which gadgets you use to modify and view files. This may also usually rely on your level of comfort with computers. Some platforms are highly user-friendly while others provide advanced features for tech geeks who are more seasoned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The breadth of Web-based computing infrastructure capabilities is enormous. Most of them have been focused on a particular field. Dropbox and SugarSync, for instance, are focused on maintaining a synchronized folder available anywhere. SpiderOak stresses safety. Some cloud storage providers, such as Apple iCloud, Google Drive, and Microsoft OneDrive, are generalists providing not only folder and file synchronization but also multimedia play and system synchronization. These products also act as collaborative apps, which provide the coediting of documents in real-time.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-right-choice-for-private-business-or-free-storage">The right choice for private, business or free storage&lt;/h2>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;h2 id="1-best-free-private-cloud-storages">1. Best (Free) Private Cloud Storages&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Even though we are cautious in using the term “free” – as we all know nothing is free. But in offering some data of yourself whilst using these services, Google Drive and others offer a free quota of data for you to use. How do they use my data? Of course, there will not be a person at Google going through your personal diary, but the&lt;a href="https://safety.google/privacy/data/">y will use that data to construct an ad-profile&lt;/a>, which means that if you, for example, type an article about how much you love dogs, you might see ads for dog food soon after. For everyone that is okay with that, it is free data, so why not?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, as I will soon explain in another blog post, you can use apps like &lt;a href="https://cryptomator.org/">Cryptomator (link)&lt;/a> to encrypt your data in the cloud (relatively) easily, meaning that the providers will not be able to use it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, our personal free Cloud Storage list goes as follows:
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="no-1--pcloud--best-free-private-cloud-storageshttpspartnerpcloudcomr22225">&lt;a href="https://partner.pcloud.com/r/22225">No. 1 – pCloud – Best (Free) Private Cloud Storages&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="imagespcloud-150x150webp">&lt;img src="https://datafortress.cloud/images/pcloud-150x150.webp" alt="">&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="heading">&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="heading-1">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>pCloud might be an entry you have not heard before, which is good because like I said before, no free service is offered completely for free. pCloud values data privacy, which they guarantee through advanced encryption and storing data in Switzerland, meaning that they are outside of the jurisdiction of the NSA or European data regulations, meaning that no government can force them to give them your data. Why should I care if I have nothing to hide? Data can be used for advertisements, industrial espionage, determining your credit score, and much more if it is in the hands of criminal entities. Additionally, pCloud offers a lifetime subscription, which beats every other contestant on the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://partner.pcloud.com/r/22225">Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="no-2--google-drive--best-free-private-cloud-storageshttpswwwgooglecomdrive">&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/drive/">No. 2 – Google Drive – Best (Free) Private Cloud Storages&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://datafortress.cloud/images/google_drive_logo-150x150.webp" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Google Drive is our number one selection for free cloud storage. It is available on many platforms and devices, offers 15 GB of free storage, and is amazingly fast. Furthermore, it offers many third-party applications to collaborate on data, and add almost any functionality you can think of.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/drive/">Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="no-3--dropbox--best-free-private-cloud-storageshttpswwwdropboxcom">&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/">No. 3 – Dropbox – Best (Free) Private Cloud Storages&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://datafortress.cloud/images/dropbox-150x150.webp" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess everyone heard of Dropbox. The company laid a special focus on file synchronization, making it the service that avoids synchronization issues the best. Also, it has good integration into almost every operating system and is, therefore, the perfect set and forget solution. The problem? It is expensive and the free data is limited to 2GB only.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/">Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="no-4--microsoft-onedrive--best-free-private-cloud-storageshttpswwwmicrosoftcomen-usmicrosoft-365onedriveonline-cloud-storage">&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/onedrive/online-cloud-storage">No. 4 – Microsoft OneDrive – Best (Free) Private Cloud Storages&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://datafortress.cloud/images/onedrive-150x150.webp" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OneDrive is automatically installed if you are using Microsoft Windows, which is &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usage_share_of_operating_systems?oldformat=true">likely you are.&lt;/a> It is nicely integrated into Office 365, meaning you can easily share, edit and save data inbetween your OneNote Notebook, Outlook E-mail and others. Using additional apps you are able to do almost anything with it. You are already using Office 365 and Windows 10? Then search no further, you will receive 1 TB free storage and will have anything you need. Still remember that Microsoft had some &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jul/11/microsoft-nsa-collaboration-user-data">privacy issues in the past, like handing over encrypted data to the NSA.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/onedrive/online-cloud-storage">Link&lt;/a>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-best-business-cloud-storages--advanced-users">2. Best Business Cloud Storages / Advanced Users&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For users that want to have more control over their data, and seek more functionality or businesses we will recommend the following.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a business, you will need way more control over your data. You will need a log, being a registry where you “write down” what users accessed which files, which will become essential to control the data flow or to craft a report in case of a data breach. Additionally, you will have to limit which department or employee can access what kind of data. It would be bad if your employees would have access to salary data for example.&lt;br>
Many businesses underestimate the importance of cloud security, as we already have shown in our &lt;a href="https://www.datafortress.cloud/cloud-services/">post about cloud computing,&lt;/a> which causes millions in lost revenue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, if not for the fact of security, custom solutions are oftentimes way cheaper compared to the private use services stated above. AWS S3 can, for example, be a thousand times cheaper compared to the quota per GB above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.datafortress.cloud/contact/">Contact us for further details&lt;/a> about the following top three business cloud storage solutions&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A custom solution with for example AWS S3 is the best choice if you already imagine a perfect workflow for your company, or you are using specific products that you want to unify. Luckily, everything is customizable and it is easy to build a custom solution that is up to your security guidelines and requirements.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;h3 id="21-self-hosted-nextcloud--best-business-cloud-storages--advanced-usershttpsnextcloudcom">&lt;a href="https://nextcloud.com/">2.1. Self-Hosted NextCloud – Best Business Cloud Storages / Advanced Users&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>NextCloud is an open-source self-hosted solution for storing data in the cloud. Being open-source, the security risk of malicious code in the product is minimal, and there are already thousands of extensions that are all for free. The broad range of developers furthermore implemented state-of-the-art security measures to truly protect your data. And the best part about open source is that it is fully customizable. We at DataFortress.cloud use it for example as a serverless data storage solution in combination with S3, and can limit it to our IP range because it is self-hosted. Definitely our best choice and basically free aside from server costs.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://nextcloud.com/">Link&lt;/a>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="22-custom-solution-like-aws-s3--best-business-cloud-storages--advanced-users">2.2. Custom solution like AWS S3 – Best Business Cloud Storages / Advanced Users&lt;/h3>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>A custom solution with for example AWS S3 is the best choice if you already imagine a perfect workflow for your company, or you are using specific products that you want to unify. Luckily, everything is customizable and it is easy to build a custom solution that is up to your security guidelines and requirements.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="23-managed-solutions-like-microsoft-onedrive--best-business-cloud-storages--advanced-users">2.3. Managed Solutions like Microsoft OneDrive – Best Business Cloud Storages / Advanced Users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>OneDrive can still be a nice choice for small- to medium-sized businesses, especially if you are using Microsoft Teams or Outlook. It is a fully managed solution, meaning that once set-up you will not need to worry about much. Problems arise from it being closed-source, meaning you will not be able to customize things, or it will be more difficult to fully understand the product to guarantee security guidelines and privacy. Additionally, data can be stored in the US, and might, therefore, be not as private as you might assume. Still, it avoids setup costs and might be a feasible option for smaller businesses.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-gb/microsoft-365/onedrive/onedrive-for-business">Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What Cloud Storage solutions do you use? Do you have any open questions or suggestions? Write us in the comments or shoot us a message via the &lt;a href="https://www.datafortress.cloud/contact/">contact page.&lt;/a>&lt;br>
We are offering a &lt;a href="https://www.datafortress.cloud/contact/">free 15-minute consultation&lt;/a> as well!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>